Good afternoon. I'm with a returning
guest, Daniel Earl, uh CEO of Highlander
Silver. Highlander is focused on silver
and gold projects across the Americas
and made a big acquisition at the end of
2025 and we're going to get into it with
Daniel. Um, hey Daniel and welcome back
to Goldfinger Capital.
>> Thanks for having me.
>> So let's get into Highlander. We spoke
in late 25. Um, obviously 2025 was a big
year for the company with some really uh
good financing, some new billionaire
investors joining the registry and then
an acquisition. So, why don't you get us
up to speed with what the company has
been doing in 2026?
>> Yeah, so we completed the acquisition of
Bear Creek Mining. Uh, that's the one
that you're referring to and that
brought two new projects into the
portfolio. So Karani which is the
largest s in development silver project
globally that was and is now our
flagship that was the key part of the
acquisition and then what came along for
the ride was the Mercedes gold silver
mine in Mexico and so that's an
operating mine we're actually growing
production there and so that was the
Bear Creek acquisition and basically
what we've been doing with Karanni this
is a a fully permitted now in
development project
is
mobilizing a team to site. So this is
led by Carlos O'Hada which was a star
recruit for Highlander Silver. He's a
very well-known and highly regarded
technical professional
um who we pulled out of Anglo-American.
He had completed building uh Anglo's
flagship development project which was
called KCO that was an over4 billion
dollar copper project. uh really
flawless execution there under Carlos
and we were able to recruit him to lead
the team at Karanni
um which is now over 300 personnel which
we've hired out of local communities
preferentially
engaged in what we would call early site
development. So that's everything from,
you know, the construction of the camp
and facilities,
uh, internal roads, access roads. Um,
we've got the, uh, the substation under
construction. We're just starting the
power line itself. Um, and we're about
to place long lead time, uh, equipment
orders, uh, for the project to commence
full construction, which would be early
2027.
And so it's a really exciting time for
the company with a hive of activity at
the Kareni project which is just a you
know it's a stunning um silver project
in terms of its scale and that scale is
is really something that we should focus
on because I think that's a tremendous
growth opportunity there but but just
stunning in terms of the economics that
are available you know in the early part
of a powerful what I think is going to
prove to be an historic you know bull
market in silver uh which we're in now.
So it's a very very exciting time for
the company.
>> So this is the largest
fully permitted silver project in the
world. So that begs the question, how
was this asset available to Highlander?
How did you manage to acquire this? And
why wasn't this mine built by the
previous company?
Well, I think in general when you're
thinking about silver assets, it it's
important to have the context that the
silver market has been in a bare market,
you know, for for the better part of the
last 15 years and we've had these brief
periods where silver has broken out and
people have made some money, but for the
most part, you know, we've been in a
bare market and the silver sector is
just structurally a high-cost sector.
And so, you know, this is like relative
to gold, for example. you know, silver
mines tend to be higher co cost relative
to the metal price uh than gold mines
tend to be. And so, you know, during
this bare market where you have sub $20
per ounce silver, this large development
project, and it's a green field
development project, has challenged
economics over that period. Okay? And so
you can see this like vividly. If you
look at the feasibility study, you know,
that that Bear Creek, who we acquired,
published in 2019, they used an $18
silver price. And at $18 silver, the net
asset value of the project was in line
with the capex. Well, that's nobody's
definition of, you know, a robust uh
compelling project. Okay. And so really
what the biggest thing that's changed um
in the silver sector is the silver
price. itself. Now we're into a
structural bull market that's going to
prove to be more durable than prior
silver, you know, markets which have
been, you know, cyclical markets and
relatively short-lived. So this is
basically, you know, the story. It's
constrained supply, okay, with a lack of
new projects against these secular
demand drivers, uh, which there are now
a whole number of these, okay? So we're
going to have a more durable market.
That's probably the biggest thing for a
project like Karanni. Okay. And then
repositioning it with a team, you know,
which is the Highlander Silver team that
has built significant developers before.
Okay. And therefore has the wherewithal
to be able to bring together the quality
personnel that you need, access the
capital, and then actually go out and
execute across one of these tier one
projects. Um, so it's a range of things.
Bear Creek itself was a distressed
situation. They had more debt than they
had equity at the time that we acquired
them. And in fact they were in default
on that debt. Okay. So they were in a
really difficult position and um and I
think to their credit they recognized
that. They recognized the opportunity in
folding into Highlander Silver and
delivering what's been a massive rerate
for their shareholders. So credit to
them for that.
>> Okay. I have a bunch of questions about
this. So silver is obviously the real
payable uh you know metal here but
there's also lead and zinc as well as
byproducts.
How important is the lead and zinc to
the economics of the mine and what are
the recoveries like?
>> Yeah. So lead and zinc together and lead
is slightly more important than zinc but
together they would only amount to less
than 15% of the economics. So they're
they're true byproducts, okay? And that
this project is entirely driven by
silver. And so if you look at our
disclosure, we actually don't even
disclose the byproducts. So we're not
doing this, you know, silver equivalent
thing where you inflate all of your
numbers. And some companies really take
advantage of that, you know, and they're
not accounting for payability. They're
not accounting for different recoveries
between the silver and those byproduct
metals. We we dispense with all of that.
Okay. So the disclosure that we give as
a company as far as I know we're the
only company doing this is purely on the
basis of silver. So when I talk about
silver production I mean silver
production not silver plus you know
whatever other other metals I can kind
of convert into silver. I mean silver
and I mean payable silver not gross
because for a lot of these projects that
are concentrate projects like our
project will be a concentrate project as
opposed to door bars you know the the
payability is not going to be 99
whatever percent. It's going to be lower
than that. Okay. And so when I talk
about silver production I'm talking
about payable silver production. And
that's another point of difference. So
basically what we're trying to do as a
company is just maintain a high level of
transparency and we're going to build up
credibility in this way over time with
investors you know that what what we say
is what they get uh with the company and
so this is this is a silver project um
you know through and through and the and
the byproducts really are you know uh uh
I think should be an afterthought for
investors.
>> Okay. And what are the recoveries of
silver here?
>> It it depends on the concentrate and the
zone that you're in, but the recoveries
are in the range of 70%.
>> Okay. Um, so what's on the agenda in
2026 in terms of improving the site
infrastructure
and
where are you at in terms of financing
the building of the mine? So, so the
region actually has good primary
infrastructure. Okay. And so this this
part of Peru has roads, it has rail, it
has power, you know, there's water
that's available. So basically what
we're putting in right now and and this
is active, you know, so we've got, if
you look on our website, you can see the
actual construction photos, uh, you
know, of the, uh, basically the
facilities and the, you know, direct
mine infrastructure that we're putting
in place. So, so those are those are
things like the camp, the facilities,
internal roads connecting up areas that
that'll be, you know, where we'll have
additional construction and operations.
We're doing the uh the earth works um
for example, where the processing plant
is going to go in, where the water
collection ponds are going to go in to
collect water so that we're not draining
groundwater for this mining operation.
um the external road. So this is the
access road, you know, which will
eventually be used, you know, for the
transport of the concentrates, the
product from this mine. Um we've got the
uh the substation going in for the power
line and then we're, you know, we're
started we're just starting putting up
the uh the towers they call them as
opposed to poles for for the actual
transmission line itself. Okay. So, so
that's all the activity that's ongoing
right now in terms of, you know, we call
it early site development and basically
to prepare for, you know, the
commencement of full-scale construction,
you know, early next year. And this is a
real point of difference. You you see
other developers out there, they're
talking about being fully permitted, you
know, and we're now a developer. Okay,
that may be technically true, but as a
practical matter, unless you actually
have the personnel in place, the team in
place, the contractors in place, and the
work ongoing, you're you're not actually
doing the work of development. And that
means that your timeline to production
is not a real timeline. With with this
company, we're actually in that
development. The construction timeline's
a real timeline, you know, and we're
going to be a future producer uh in this
company.
>> Very good. Um what is the potential for
growth? Right now it's over 400 million
ounces of silver, but I imagine there's
a lot of room for growth and is that a
focus for Highlander to do more
exploration?
>> Oh. Oh, abs abs. Absolutely. and and we
published um we we wanted to paint the
picture for people um and we actually
published geoysical results and this is
from a comprehens well a series of
comprehensive surveys that would be you
know the first across a number of
categories in the history of this
project. Okay. So you think about like
that context that I provided in terms of
like how this project fit into prior
cycles which were dominated by bare
market periods. Okay. It meant that with
a large endowment in outcrop, they
didn't bother exploring for what was
concealed by overlying cover. And it
turns out, and you can see it vividly,
um, because you get a sharp geoysical
contrast between the host rocks and, you
know, the mineralization.
Um, and what you can see vividly is just
how much larger this system is. the
majority of it underneath shallow cover
30 to 40 meters of cover which has never
been explored
than the portion that has been explored
which is basically within a valley where
you've had erosion get down to the
underlying host rocks. Okay. So it's
already the largest silver endowment
that's actually in development. But I
think when you look at that map, you can
see an opportunity terms of the
footprint of the system relative to the
drilling that you could potentially grow
this by multiple times over a period of
years. And so we've got six rigs on site
now and we'll have our first, you know,
assay results, drilling results, uh, in
the next month or so. And um we're going
to be demonstrating
uh exactly that potential through
drilling results with with step out and
high impact expiration that we have
planned for this year.
>> And what's the plan to do a resource,
you know, update um on the project that
will include some of this new drilling?
Yeah, we'll listen, we'll we'll be
updating the resources in in Q4, but
we'll be updating resources every year
and and this isn't going to be a story
where all the growth is delivered in one
year because of the scale. Okay, we need
45 rigs here to drill this thing off in
one year. We've got six rigs. So, what
we're are we are going to do is we're
going to have high impact expiration.
People will get a feel for what the
growth opportunity looks at. um only a
portion of that is actually going to be
drilled into resource categories um
that'll be reflected you know in in an
update in Q4 along with the feasibility
study that'll restate reserves and
remember the prior feasibility study was
based on $18 silver spot silver is in
the 60s consensus pricing even uh is in
the 40s so rerating you know those
reserves or reclassifying resource
reserves rather from a very large
resource. The resource is almost double
the size of the existing reserves at $18
silver. Reclassifying those reserves at
a higher metal price will deliver
significant growth on it on its own.
>> So this is an epiothermal silver lead
zinc system.
Uh is there porefree potential here? Is
that something that you're interested
in? Uh or is that not a focus at this
point in time?
>> No, no, that's that's a great question.
Yeah, like so so basically this this is
part of a belt uh that extends, you
know, basically from Karanni uh down
through San Raphael. San Raphael is the
largest tin producer in the world. This
is Msur's operation. Okay. And that's
not very far away. That's basically
their claim package adjoins our southern
claim package. Okay. So, this is very
nearby and and it's a related style of
mineralization
and this belt extends all the way down
into Peru or into Bolivia rather. We're
we're in Peru cross the border with Peru
down into Bolivia uh where you do in
fact have these poor free deposits. And
so when you start, you know, looking at
the big picture, you realize that the
the source of the mineralization here is
going to be a porefree depth. And then
depending on um the you know system
depth and the host rocks you're going to
have these different expressions of
mineralization ranging you know from
porefree copper
uh through to
uh this base metal mineralization and
then the highest level expressions are
going to be this epithermal press metal
dominated mineralization. that full
suite is going to be on offer here. It's
just never been explored in the history
of Karanni. Nobody's done an airborne
geoysical survey. Nobody's done that
deeper drilling um to go and test uh you
know these other styles of
mineralization on the property package.
We're going to do all of that.
>> Very exciting. So you acquired a massive
resource and a huge huge package that
needs to be explored further and
properly with modern uh tools in a
prolific uh belt in South America. Uh
very very exciting. Um so tell us about
the key milestones for Highlander over
the coming months. What are the key
catalysts for the company and the things
that shareholders should be focused on?
>> Well, well, maybe let's do projects and
then and then corporate. So, if you
think in terms of the projects, you
know, Karanni being the flagship
project. So, we've got drill results
that'll be coming in the very near term.
Okay. And then we've got a feasibility
study with the resource update, the
reserve update, and most crucially, it's
just a, you know, a vastly different
approach than the prior feasibility
study. We talked about how the metal
price will be higher, but we're we're
we're employing a stage development
approach. This is just a smarter, more
capital efficient, and most importantly,
faster way to bring on a first phase of
production at Karanni. Okay. So, we're
basically cutting the project in half in
this stage development feasibility
study. It's permitted for 30,000 tons
per day. We'll deliver 15,000 tons per
day in the first stage over the first
four years. That's still tier one level
silver production. 10 million ounces of
payable
silver, not silver equivalent production
over those first four years. So 10
million each year. And then we'll double
the capacity in year five. And what this
allows us to do is is bring the capex
in. So instead of the capex going up
from the 2019 number, which was $580
million, the capex will come in. So
that'll be a lower number. and and then
most importantly it it allows us to
bring this production on in two years of
construction and that's really the key
in terms of driving evaluation rate is
going from development to production.
Okay. So so so those are the catalysts.
Our San Louie project is in permitting.
Our Mercedes project it did 30 this is
an operating mine in Mexico. Okay. Gold
mine. It did 30,000 ounces last year. uh
you can see that we're sort of 10 to 15%
above that. We've outlined previously a
two-year plan to raise that production
profile by 50%. Okay. So, that's what's
happening on on on the project side.
Corporately,
um you know, the the the the
key catalyst
um in terms of growing the liquidity are
the index ads. We've got a series of
indexes that we're going to be added to,
you know, at the end of August, in
September, you know, November, December.
There's a series of index ads and these
are meaningful. So something like the
GDXJ, for example, that could represent
on its own 5 million shares of demand,
and then you've got uh, you know,
another five million shares of demand
uh, between the other indexes. So index
ads will help build out the liquidity,
you know, provide a lift in terms of
some buying there. Um, and then
outlining the financing solution for the
Karanni project, you know, so if you
think of our balance sheet right now,
we've got a 100 million on the balance
sheet. That's the same number that we
had in Q1. It's the same number because
the free cash flow from the gold
production is offsetting the spending
that we're doing in silver development.
So 100 million there. We'll have a a
project finance facility that'll be in
the range of, you know, $30 to $325
million.
And then we've got free cash flow coming
in. Okay? And then think about that
capex number, you know, being uh in and
around a $450 million number. Okay? So
outlining that financing solution for
the market so the market can have
confidence that we're well financed to
deliver this project. you know, when we
go back and we look at the life cycle of
successful mining companies, you know,
re a recent example and maybe even the
poster child, um, would be a company
like Artemis, you know, run by Steven
Dean, who's one of the great minds, I
think, in our sector. Um, but that is a
a shining example of uh successful
development in the gold sector in that
case. And the key catalyst for them that
really accelerated the reate higher was
putting the financing package in place.
You know, another one would be Skina
where you just see this inflection
higher in terms of the reate. You know,
we want to bring that to the market in
the coming months and deliver that same
acceleration in terms of re rer rate for
ourselves. Okay. And that and that's
about rerating as a developer. But the
big opportunity for our shareholders is
rerating all the way to a producer
multiple. Okay. We've we've never seen a
wider discount
for developers relative to producers.
And nobody's complaining because all the
valuations are good across the board in
a bull market. But we've never seen a
wider discount for developers relative
to producers than we see in this market.
Okay? And that means that the big reate
comes on actually going to production.
For a lot of developers, that's a 10
times rate. Okay? So that's that's why
it's so important for us, you know, time
to production, you know, to really
minimize that and mitigate the risks
against delivering on that.
>> Wow, that's very exciting.
uh you have a lineup of powerful
catalysts and key milestones over the
next year, but also you have all these
inclusions into the you know GDXJ and
the SILJ and the S&P index and uh I mean
I guess there's no guarantees but it
seems like Highlander is a very good
candidate for all of those for you know
for for all those exchange traded funds
and that could potentially bring in uh
quite a bit of buying pressure and
volume into the stock uh for you know
over the next three to four months here
in 2026. So it looks like Highlander um
h well obviously had a fantastic 2025.
It had a consolidation throughout the
first half of 2026, a 50% retracement
off the all-time high, but now it
appears like the sector it's embarking
on the next leg higher with a lot of
good reasons why the share price can go
higher. For for those investors who look
at Highlander and say, "It's too
expensive. I can't I can't buy a $7
stock. I can't buy a billion dollar
market cap." What would you tell them?
Well, look, I mean, the stock was $10.5
before the correction. We we we've
basically been in an uptrend since the
beginning of 25 when we launched the
company, right? Right up until February
28th, you know, when this stock was at
$10.5 and the Iran conflict broke out.
Okay? And that basically started a
downtrend as it did as it did for most
of the sector. Okay? And then that and
then that was exasperated by some
corporate selling. We had to clean out
some positioning in our stock that we
inherited from bear greed which was a
pretty messy structure. And of course
you know that that selling you always
have to clear uh at the worst possible
moment when you're dealing with
corporates and they won't sell at the
top they have to sell at the bottom and
they have to sell immediately. So that's
you know that's part for the course. We
knew that we we we would face that kind
of risk with the acquisition. It was
part of what we you know kind of
considered as board. So you know we
cleaned out positioning. We dealt with
the uh you know sector selloff, clean
out positioning amid that and then we
got hit with the political risk flare up
in Peru. Okay. So we were coming through
the election cycle there's a surprise
left-wing challenge. Okay, that emerged
in the first round. So this is going
back to April and then basically through
April, May, June into July, you have
this additional kind of overhang of
political risk in a market that doesn't
want to hear about risks. when you have
the whole sector uh and especially
political risk when you have the whole
sector trading off. Fortunately, the
election was concluded, you know, with
the new president Fuji my being declared
in early July and she's a right-wing
candidate. Her actual election platform
was about bringing in FDI to boost the
economy in Peru uh by cutting permitting
timelines in half in the country uh
improving the infrastructure, you know,
improving the security situation. Those
are all things that go to our benefit.
Okay? And that and that's really what
has catalyzed the beginning of a rebound
together with the rest of the sector. So
if you look at our stock now, we've
actually broken the downtrend. We're
into a new uptrend and just getting back
to the prior high, you know, is $10.5.
There's way way way more upside beyond
that.
>> Very good. Okay. So that's Highlander.
Let's talk about another company that
you're involved with, Stardust.
Uh, this is a new one on Goldfinger
Capital. It's probably a new one for a
bunch of people. Tell us about Stardust.
Uh, you know, Metal Corp.
>> Yeah, it's totally off the radar. Like,
like this isn't even listed on an
exchange that most people can actually
trade on. It's it's on the Canadian
Securities. They're working on their
TSXV listing. Uh, that'll really help. I
think most investors are able to trade
on that market uh in our space. Um and
and so that'll be important. It is a
micro cap, you know, so it's still under
a 100 million market cap even though
it's been on a bit of a tear. This has
been catalyzed by the IPO of Pier
Lance's Cadillac Mines. I think you know
Cadillac Mines for anyone in your
audience who's not following this
company I think this could be the most
important gold developer in the Canadian
gold sector Cadillac Mines okay so it's
a 2 and a half billion market cap but
they have an ambition to uh get to a
total resource base of over 10 million
ounces
this is right in the heart of the
Kirkland Lake camp and then produce from
that you know over 500,000 ounces per
year so out and out tier one gold
project, okay, in the heart of Kirkland
Lake, one of the most prolific gold
camps uh in in Canada. So, Cadillac
Mines could become the most significant
of all of the Canadian gold developers.
Okay. And Stardust basically is sitting
right next to it. In fact, Stardust has
some of the key infrastructure from the
historical mining
of the you know of the of the flagship
asset of Cadillac Mines which is called
Kerr Addison. So on the Stardust side,
you actually have a shaft that's fully
it's got the head frame, it's got the
services, the guides and everything. The
hoist is all still in place. You've got
the uh uh you know the disturbed land in
the former production, including the
tailing storage facility as well, which
probably itself is hosting a million
ounces. And then you've got the
continuation of the very same geology. A
lot of the expiration growth at
Cadillac's Kur Addison goes right up to
the property boundary, which is I mean I
mean it's talking about right up we're
only a couple hundred meters um from the
edge of their pitch shell uh to the
property boundary. Uh but but that same
geology just continues right the way
through. And that's what Stardust is
embarking on a drilling program on right
now. So, they're drilling. They've got a
resource update coming, you know,
following the listing that'll be, I
think, probably in the next couple
months and then they'll be on their way
um as a company. So, that's that's
Stardust. It's totally it's completely
off the radar.
>> What's the total shares outstanding
right now for Stardust?
>> It's about if it look at fully diluted.
So, I never look at basic, but but fully
diluted, you've got less than 60 million
shares.
>> Okay. So, it's about 100 million CAD uh
fully diluted.
>> Okay.
Um and it's So, they're applying to list
on the TSXV. Is is that going to occur
in the next few weeks, you think? I
>> I think it's in the next couple weeks.
>> Okay. So, people can can buy that if
they don't
>> I think they'll be able Yeah, they'll be
able to buy it soon.
>> Okay.
Um and then Andina Copper, another
company that you're involved with. You
know a thing or two about pfree copper
in Latin America. What's the update on
Andina?
>> Yeah, it's super exciting. It's a very
large
uh copper system, copper porefree
system. Um there's actually an even more
advanc part of the system is owned by a
private company called Monero Cobra. are
partnered and the project's operated by
Riotinto which Riotinto one of the
global majors but importantly they're
trying to rebalance their portfolio
toward copper under an aggressive new
CEO and so that side of the property
boundary has a two billion ton endowment
already reportedly this is a private
company obviously okay and then on the
end side you've got um I think the
better part of the system certainly
you've got a larger footprint in terms
of the anomaly that they control and
this is a project I've been following
this for over 10 years almost 15 years
I've been following this project I tried
to acquire it myself in a prior life now
in reference to Andina I'm purely a
strategic adviser and I've got a a
shareholding as well but um but Andina
has um you know they're early on in a
drilling program which has returned you
know some pretty stunning results from
surface or near surface
meet intervals that are hundreds of
meters of better than half a percent
copper and up to a percent copper um in
uh uh in in just the early days of of
what is going to grow to be a large
drilling program here on this project.
So I think when you when you look at the
big picture, you're you you're you're
basically looking at an unfolding tier
one copper discovery in Colombia.
Colombia is a frontier jurisdiction to
be clear, but it's got a right-wing
government in place. Um, and uh, and so
it's an exciting story to watch in
copper space.
>> Yeah, it's actually one of my favorites
and one of my top picks. They had drill
results out this week. Another really
good long interval of near surface point
4.5% copper with some higher grade
areas. So, yeah. Yeah, great one.
>> It's a great story and it's um you know
I think what you saw is is is some some
pretty big volume which tells me when
you have great results like that and
then you have a big pick up in volume
that what you're getting is an
institution you know taking the uh
liquidity opportunity there. That's not
a a read on the drill results
themselves. Those are great drill
results.
>> Exactly. Yeah. Exactly. And it's holding
above a dollar. So I think we'll chew
through the volume and hopefully uh
resume the uptrend. Uh so final question
Daniel pretty active summer across the
junior mining sector across markets in
general the world. It's an active time.
Uh obviously we were in some summer
doldrums there uh for a couple months.
Hopefully we've just managed to you know
lift off and come out of the doldrums.
Um, but what's your take on the
environment right now? I mean,
obviously, you talk to a lot of people,
you talk to bankers, you talk to other
corporate executives. Where are we at
right now in the junior mining sector
and in the gold and silver, uh, you
know, cycles as well?
>> Yeah. Well, well, look, um, I think in
terms of calling the macro, it's very
difficult to do because everything
hinges on, you know, or at a high level
anyway. uh there's a big influence from
what happens in the Middle East and
that's just impossible for anyone to
call. Um so you know setting it you know
assuming that that gets resolved in a
kind of a reasonable way then I think
you know the rest of the call is is
relatively easier. I would be fading you
know these inflation and rate hike
risks. I don't think that we're going to
get these rate hikes and I think you
know by this time next year we might
actually be talking about rate cuts and
so I think in terms of the macro
environment um you know it's going to be
very supportive for precious metals the
central back uh bank buying okay post
Iran conflict cleaning up and you know a
lot of the central banks had to put on
pause or even sell some of or leverage
some of their precious metals to be able
to defend their currencies. I think post
that conflict
um cleaning up I think they go back to
the bid and we've already seen that that
China is back to buying gold
aggressively. I think you get the rest
of the banks uh coming back now with
more impetus because we have yet another
signal that the geopolitical framework
you know the ability to rely on the US
financial system is continuing to be
challenged. Okay. So I think the the the
framework for the pre precious metals
that supported the bull market to date
comes back with a vengeance. Now you
know silver in the short run behaves
like a beta play on gold. Okay? So
that's basically going to dictate how
silver trades. But remember in the long
run we've got these secular demand
trends against constrained supply. And
so if you're bullish and you're reading
these headlines about Nvidia getting
creative and working with these big
global financial institutions to secure
half a trillion dollars
uh for this ongoing AI and data center
uh buildout and then all the grid
investment that's got to go along to
support that and then the advent of with
SpaceX a new space economy and the
pickup in defense spending. These are
all areas uh which are going to be
heavily uh dependent on silver supplies.
Okay. So I I think you know you look at
the market right now um it's basically
treating silver like it's another metal
whereas in copper there's a recognition
that we can see in copper pricing at
all-time highs that it's more than a
regular metal. that's actually, you
know, a true strategic metal that is
required to wire together and electrify
all these growth areas that coming to
silver. I don't know when it's going to
come, but at some point silver pricing
is going to reflect how important the
metal is. And uh so I think it's look,
I'm bullish on precious metals. I'm more
bullish than I was before. Uh but
especially on silver, I think it's uh uh
got a very bright future.
You know, silver price targets are
always tricky and a lot of numbers get
thrown around. I mean, just earlier this
year, silver hit above $100 an ounce for
the first time in history. It's hard for
me to fathom that that was the top. Um,
it feels like there's got to be another
wave coming. It's just a matter of when.
How high do you think the silver price
could actually
go eventually? Like is there a price
where it's just like okay the supply
will really come online than at that
price? Co calling peak pricing is
basically impossible but but it's much
easier to understand floor pricing.
Okay. And and and what I'd encourage
everyone to do is is look at the Q2
financials of the silver sector. Okay,
which you know a lot a number of these
companies have most of these companies
have already reported and especially
look at where the growth might come.
It's not in the seniors that's going to
be in your in your smaller companies
your mid tiers and then your junior
producers and just look at how high the
costs are. You know the these companies
the smaller producers are not making
money at $60 silver. Okay? And so
they're not generating free cash flow
that they can then redeploy into growth.
They've got to go to the market for
that.
And you know these swing producers that
have been a lot of the new IPO kind of
stories and so on um that have come to
the market or been reactivated and so
on, they they need even higher prices
than that and costs are going higher.
Like we're we're at the beginning of I I
think it's going to prove to be an
historic capital inflation cycle for the
mining sector and it's going to be the
most acute in the United States. Okay?
Because you're competing again. First of
all, you've got a tight um you know,
tight kind of labor um situation to
begin with, but then you're competing
for all those key you know like
difficult to secure uh contractors and
trades and skills like electrical and
plumbing and piping and all you know key
construction.
um against this um you know overfunded
uh you know bonanza of the AI buildout
and all the infrastructure build out to
support that and so you're going to have
this incredible amount of cost inflation
in the United States and that's just
going to mean that even more of that
growth uh requires higher pricing.
Canada is similar story, not as bad
because the Canadian economy of course
not as strong as the US economy. Okay?
But you have a lot of mining activity.
You've got now pipelines that are going
to be built. You've got LG projects that
are going to be built in the same region
as you've got these mining projects. And
the mining economy obviously is in a
bull market. So capex inflation in the
United States, capex inflation in
Canada, it's going to be in Mexico as
well. Um it'll be contained in Latin
America. Okay. So you you'll see, you
know, um a fraction of the kind of
inflation, but all of these costs are
going higher. I think floor pricing is
already way higher for silver than
people realize it is. Um and it's going
to be growing at about 15% per year. So
like I think it's more important as an
investor to focus on that. Like we're at
$65 silver, let's call it right now. I
think we're basically at the floor uh in
terms of like the ability, you know, of
this industry to deliver growth. We need
higher prices. So even though it feels
good, that's the reality in terms of
funding the build out of this sector.
>> Those are some powerful um comments that
you just made. I hope the viewers
relisten to that a couple of times
because it's pretty profound. If $65
silver is the floor and there's a lot of
good logic that does uh you know support
that concept, then what could the peak
be possibly at some point in the future?
And it might not be that long before we
get above $100 an ounce, you know,
again. Um and then what are the
implications
for silver miners if that if that does
play out? And the thing you said about
the data center buildout, the the
numbers are are mind-boggling. I mean, I
don't know how to think about a half a
trillion dollars in capex spending
uh from one company. I mean, it's
absolutely mind-blowing.
>> It's not gonna it's not going to happen,
right? Like they they can't I mean, I'm
sure that they can raise the capital,
but in terms of like actually putting
the boots on the ground and the trades
on the projects to actually get all of
that capital spent efficiently, it's not
going to happen. like try try try
finding like uh I don't know where
you're based but anywhere in the United
States try finding you know pulling
together a team to to put up a project.
It's it's already extremely difficult
and it's going to get dramatically
worse.
>> Yeah, I'm in Florida. We've got our own
problems and we've got a uh
>> candidate for governor who's against all
data centers. So that'll be interesting
as well. Um Daniel, thank you so much
for your time. was a great conversation
and I look forward to speaking again in
a few months.
>> Awesome. Thanks for having me.
Appreciate it.
>> Cheers.